Farman Kaziakhmedov

Backend Software Engineer

Contacts

Phone: +7(977)590-90-31

Email:

farman.kaziakhmedov@gmail.com

Github: subher0

Skills

Java



SQL'



Git



Python



Docker



React



Java software engineer with 5 years of experience in developing concurrent web applications using Java SE 11. Proficient at developing apps, designed for high loads. Experienced user of linux (Ubuntu) and Git. Successfully migrated the Java EE 6 project to java 11, powered by Spring Boot and Hibernate, which improved code maintainability and the speed of development. Currently, responsible for the migration of legacy monolithic codebase to a new one on a microservice architecture.

Work History

2021-07 -Current

Backend Software Engineer

Revolut, Moscow

- Updated old code bases to modern development standards
- Participated in migration of legacy monolithic architecture to microservices
- Delivered unit and integration tested systems within customer-prescribed timeframes

2018-03 -2021-07

Lead Java Developer

Tinkoff Insurance, Moscow

- Worked closely with customers to understand their needs
- Migrated the project from Java EE 6 to Java SE 11
 + Spring Boot 2.0 on microservice architecture
- Lead the team consisting of 4 software developers, 1 Analyst and 3 QA Engineers
- Developed a flexible system (React front-end and Kotlin back-end) for business users to customize the behaviour of BPM platform
- Trained an XGBoost model to reduce the costs of communications with potential clients

2017-04 -2018-03

Java Developer

Self Employed, Moscow

- Migrated Python project to Java 8 + Spring Boot
- Worked with OAuth 2.0 to enable users to authorise through Facebook and Google API
- Implemented a recommendation system based on collaborative filtering powered by Apache Mahoot

 Designed a document generation system based on user input and preexisting data, powered by Aspose and Apache POI libraries

Education

2013-09 - Bachelor of Science: Production Automation

Bauman Moscow State University - Moscow